in its truest form ice cream is made up
of milk cream sugar and a stabilizer
with this knowledge I'm going to create
three low calorie vanilla ice cream
recipes that taste nearly as amazing as
the full fat stuff and get increasingly
better with each variation let's get
into it let's start with a pint on a
scale and into it add 240 grams one
percent milk 200 grams almond milk and 5
grams of vanilla extract for milk I use
Fairlife because it has double the
protein of regular milk but the same
amount of calories however since
Fairlife doesn't make one percent milk
anymore I buy a half gallon of both fat
free and two percent and add 120 grams
of each you can also use regular milk
for these recipes you will just miss out
on about half of the protein per recipe
put the Pint off to the side and put a
small bowl on your scale to it add 45
grams swerve one gram xanthan gum and 1
gram of salt the urethra tall or swerve
is going to act like our sugar and the
xanthan Gomez are stabilizer which
creates a smoother texture and prevents
Ice Crystal formation mix these three
ingredients up with a spoon or Fork then
take a frother or an immersion blender
and start mixing the wet ingredients in
the Pint while they are mixing slowly
add the dry ingredients into the mixture
doing this while mixing is going to help
dissolve the xanthan gum without having
it Clump up up and will make for a silky
smooth final product once all the dry
ingredients have been poured continue
mixing for an additional 90 seconds when
finished put a cap on your pint and
freeze it for 24 hours if you have a
bunch of pints in your freezer like I do
I suggest getting some masking tape and
labeling your ice cream with a sharpie
before throwing it in the freezer this
way you know which pint is which when
choosing your ice cream for the day when
you are ready to eat grab your pint and
rinse the outside of it under hot water
for one minute dry the Pint off load it
up and hit the ice cream function I have
tried all the creamy settings and the
ice cream function is what I found
worked the best in a double blind
control trial I did in my kitchen
however texture preferences are
individual so if there's another setting
you prefer feel free to use that one
once the first spin is done it looks
like this it definitely needs another
re-spin so back into the creamy it goes
after the re-spin the vanilla ice cream
is ice cream pint consistency but if you
are a fan of vanilla soft serve I would
run the respin one more time this recipe
is lowest calorie out of the group while
also being the most cost effective but
we can definitely up the flavor taste
and texture so let's move on to the next
recipe into a pint at 440 grams one
percent milk and 5 grams of vanilla
extract it's a subtraction of almond
milk for the addition of purely cow's
milk is going to improve the ice cream's
consistency while also decreasing Ice
Crystal formation put the Pint off to
the side and put a small bowl on your
scale to it add 45 grams swerve one
grams xanthan gum and one gram of Salt
by the way if you prefer another
sweetener feel free to use it in these
recipes instead mix the dry ingredients
thoroughly and while the frother is
running slowly add the dry ingredients
to the Pine once all the dry ingredients
have been added mix for an additional 90
seconds put the top on and freeze for 24
hours when it's time to eat rinse off
the outside of the Pint load it into the
creamy and run it on the ice cream
setting while you wait consider ordering
my cookbook to get access to over 100
delicious recipes including the ones in
this video and receive all update for
free if you want future recipes before
everyone else get the gift that keeps on
giving and order today with the link in
my pin comment load the Pint right back
up hit that respawn button one more time
for ice cream consistency or two more
times for That Sweet succulent soft
serve this version undoubtedly surpasses
the good version and taste by several
notches yet the next recipe will make
these first two look like mere common
folks for this recipe we are going to
grab a high sided container and load it
up on a scale you will find out why we
are using this instead of the Pint very
soon to it add 430 grams of two percent
milk and egg yolk and 5 grams vanilla
extract even though ice cream is made up
of four main ingredients many ice cream
brands also add an emulsifier to their
recipes this is because it helps bind
different liquids together which creates
a smoother and creamier consistency that
you can taste with every single bite
after several side-by-side comparisons
of no egg yolk versus egg yolk I even
did a blind taste test to make sure my
mouth wasn't telling me lies
all right now like move them around and
so I don't know what's what hello
pretty smooth
pretty smooth I gotta say
if this isn't the egg one
I would be shocked super smooth feels
like fattier in the mouth and uh like
Zero ice crystals whatsoever
no egg
that's what I thought
with egg
telling you egg yolk worth it 100 love
it if you don't want to use an egg yolk
for whatever reason that's okay just add
15 extra grams of milk this is where we
take this recipe over the top vanilla
beans if you have ever tried vanilla ice
cream next to vanilla bean ice cream you
know how much of a difference these
little sticks of Heaven can make in the
overall flavor it is important you get a
good quality vanilla bean and I have
linked the ones I am using in the
description below we are going to grab
one of our vanilla beans and using a
knife cut it in half and open up the
bean then using the knife we are going
to scoop out half of the seeds by just
scraping along the inside drop them into
the wet ingredients and put the other
half of the vanilla bean into an
airtight container or bag to make sure
it stays fresh once these vanilla pods
are empty don't throw them away you can
make homemade vanilla extract that will
be miles cheaper than what you buy at
the store add a bowl to your scale and
add 45 grams swerve 1 grams and then gum
and one gram of salt mix those
ingredients together for this recipe I
highly recommend using an immersion
blender if you have one it not only
incorporates the xanthan gum more easily
but it also thickens up the mixture by
emulsifying it more than the frother
ever could I found that if you just use
the frother most of the vanilla beans
will sink to the bottom what you can do
to circumvent this issue is take the
Pint out of the freezer after about an
hour of freezing and swirl the mixture
around for 10 to 15 seconds since the
liquid has thickened in the freezer the
vanilla beans will now hold in place
like you used an immersion blender with
that said using an immersion blender
start blending the wet ingredients while
slowly pouring the dry ingredients into
the Container once all dry ingredients
are poured in mix for an additional 90
seconds and dump the liquid into a pint
just look how thick the cream is already
I will probably be using an immersion
blender for all creamy recipes going
forward now throw that pint into the
freezer side note the best investment I
ever made was buying extra pints because
I always have ice cream that could be
made without having to wait 24 hours I
will also leave links down in the
description for extra pints as well 24
hours later it time to eat run it under
hot water for 60 seconds load it into
the creamy and take her for a spin on
the ice cream setting repeat for desired
consistency and you now have the most
luxurious vanilla ice cream that our
creamy has ever whipped up oh my God
yes each of these recipes have their own
utility and can all be made in the same
amount of time but if you were to make
just one I would have to go with the
king of the vanilla bean cream vanilla
ice cream is great any time of day but
these 160 calorie pints of ice cream
test the boundaries and make for more
variety in a diet having multiple
options is a key factor to consistent
adherence to a diet and you can check
out that video for those recipes here
until next time deuces